Inventory of the J.E. Morpurgo Papers 1937-2000
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Book reviews, n.d., 1938-1980. (Box-folder 6:33-54)
  - Review of G.B. Warden, Boston, 1689-1776, 1970., 4 items. (Box-folder 6:39)
    Includes correspondence between managing editor of J.E.M., Dent and Sons Publishers and J.E.M. regarding his review of the book. Dent was considering a British edition of the work, but J.E.M. advised against it.
  - Review essay on Carl Bode, ed., The Best of Thoreau's Journals and Ralph Waldo Emerson, 1971., 7 items. (Box-folder 6:40)
    Includes correspondence between editors at The Times Literary Supplement and J.E.M. Deals with J.E.M.'s review and his response to criticism from one reader.
  - Book reviews, 1972., 5 items. (Box-folder 6:41)
    Authors and titles of works reviewed are listed on the front of the folder.
  - Review of W.E. Williams' Allen Lane: A Personal Portrait, 3 items. (Box-folder 6:42)
    Published in New Statesman under the title "King of the Castle." Includes acknowledgment from journal and proofs.
  - Review of David Irving's Hitler's War, ca. 1977., 6 item. (Box-folder 6:43)
    Includes correspondence between J.E.M. and Irving regarding Irving's his claim that "Hitler did not order killing of Jews."
  - Reviews of Christopher Hibbert's The Great Mutiny, and Philip Mason's A Shaft of Sunlight, 1978., 3 items. (Box-folder 6:44)
    Published in the Yorkshire Post. Includes letter from the literary editor regarding the reviews.
  - Essay on Olivia Manning's The Battle Lost and Won, 1980., 2 items. (Box-folder 6:45)
    Published in Yorkshire Arts under the title Book of the Year.
  - Assorted book reviews, n.d., 9 items. (Box-folder 6:46)
    Authors and titles of books reviewed are listed on the front of the folder.
  - Assorted book reviews, n.d., 9 items. (Box-folder 6:47)
    Authors and titles of the books reviewed are listed on the front of the folder.
  - Assorted book reviews, n.d., 15 items. (Box-folder 6:48)
  - Assorted book reviews on American subjects, n.d., 31 items. (Box-folder 6:49)
  - Review of Commager's The American Mind, n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 6:50)
    Draft.
  - Book reviews written for The Times Literary Supplement, daily Telegraph, and other publications, n.d., 73 items. (Box-folder 6:51)
  - Additional book reviews from various publications, n.d., 25 items. (Box-folder 6:52)
  - Reviews of stage shows, n.d., 3 items. (Box-folder 6:53)
    Includes reviews on: "At Your Service," "Arsenic and Old Lace," and "Ladies in Waiting."
  - Review of Denis Welland, ed., The United States: A Companion to American Studies, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 6:54)
  Series 14: Papers relating to books by J.E.M.
- Papers relating to books by J.E.M., n.d., 1946-1995. (Box-folder 7-8:11)
    Subseries 14.1: Correspondence and drafts
  - Correspondence and drafts, n.d., 1946-1995. (Box-folder 7-8)
    - Notes and correspondence concerning the publication of The Autobiography of Leigh Hunt, 1946-1957., 6 items. (Box-folder 7:1)
    - Correspondence and drafts of revisions related to J.E.M. and Russel Nye's History of America, 1951-1986., 144 items. (Box-folder 7:2)
    - Correspondence concerning various revisions and reprints of J.E.M. and Russel Nye's History of the United States, 1975-1981., 37 items. (Box-folder 7:3)
      Includes letters regarding a Japanese edition.
    - Correspondence with Charles Forte, Esq. about the possibility of J.E.M. working on Forte's memoirs, 1959-1960., 24 items. (Box-folder 7:4)
    - Typed notes and drafts of work with Charles Forte, n.d., 9 items. (Box-folder 7:5)
      Some of the material may have been Forte's own writing-no indication of authorship was made.
    - Notes and drafts for work with Charles Forte, n.d. (Box-folder 7:6)
    - Introduction to William Cobbett, Journal of a Year's Residence in the U.S.A. Centaur Press., 1963, 8 items. (Box-folder 7:7)
      Includes correspondence between Centaur and J.E.M. regarding publication.
    - William Cobbett in America, 1984., 2 items. (Box-folder 7:8)
      An expanded introduction to Cobbett's America. London: Folio Society (pp. xi-xxxi). Includes draft.
    - William Cobbett in America, n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 7:9)
      Two drafts. One labelled: Cobbett Introduction.
    - Notes and synopsis for biography of author William Cobbett, n.d., 5 items. (Box-folder 7:10)
    - Items relating to J.E.M.'s The Road to Athens, 1961-1966., 138 items. (Box-folder 7:11)
      Correspondence, reviews, and proofs.
    - Account of travels through Western Europe for The Road to Athens, n.d., 8 items. (Box-folder 7:12)
      Includes maps, charts, and J.E.M.'s essay Modern Greece.
    - Items relating to J.E.M.'s edition of James Fenimore Cooper's The Spy, 1962-1968., 49 items. (Box-folder 7:13)
      Correspondence, reviews, and proofs. Includes unsigned copy of agreement with Oxford University Press, 1963.
    - J.E.M.'s foreword to Jella Lepman's A Bridge of Common Books, 1968., 1 item. (Box-folder 7:14)
    - J.E.M.'s Treason at West Point: The Arnold-Andre Conspiracy, 1975., 3 items. (Box-folder 7:15)
      New York: Mason/Charter (169 pp.). Also includes a copy of the poem The Ballad of Major Andre, and J.E.M.'s outline.
    - Correspondence concerning publication of For If It Prosper and Treason at West Point, 1994-1995., 4 items. (Box-folder 7:16)
    - Correspondence leading up to the publication of the biography of Allen Lane, 1972-1979., 116 items. (Box-folder 8:1)
    - Notes, reviews, and correspondence relating to biography of Allen Lane, 1979., 37 items. (Box-folder 8:2)
      Includes photographs of reception introducing the book.
    - Correspondence concerning the biography of Allen Lane, 1979-1980., 27 items. (Box-folder 8:3)
    - Correspondence concerning reaction to and royalties for Allen Lane: King Penguin, 1979-1983., 73 items. (Box-folder 8:4)
    - J.E.M. speech on biography of Allen Lane, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 8:5)
    - Material submitted to publisher's designers for a new edition by Flyfield of Charles Lamb's Charles Lamb and Elia, 1993., 2 items. (Box-folder 8:6)
      A previous edition was published by Penguin in 1948. Includes Part 1: Mr. Charles Lamb and the introduction to the original edition.
    - Part 2 of Charles Lamb and Elia - He Serves Up His Friends, 1993., 1 item. (Box-folder 8:7)
    - Part 3 of Charles Lamb and Elia - The Irate St. Charles, 1993., 1 item. (Box-folder 8:8)
    - Part 4 of Charles Lamb and Elia - More House Lamb Than Grass Lamb, 1993, 1 item. (Box-folder 8:9)
    - Part 5 of 1993 Charles Lamb and Elia - Juices of Meats, Innocent Vanities and Jest, 1993., 1 item. (Box-folder 8:10)
    - Notes on Some Contemporaries, for 1993 edition of Charles Lamb and Elia, 1993., 2 items. (Box-folder 8:11)
    Subseries 14.2: Reviews
  - Reviews, n.d, 1949-1981 (Box-folder 8:12-21)
    - Reviews of J.E.M.'s The Autobiography of Leigh Hunt, 1949., 9 items. (Box-folder 8:12)
      Cresset Press. Includes front part of an original dustjacket.
    - Reviews of J.E.M.'s edition of Charles Lamb and Elia, 1948., 5 items. (Box-folder 8:13)
      Penguin Press.
    - Reviews of J.E.M.'s American Excursion, 1949., 14 items. (Box-folder 8:14)
    - Henry Steele Commager: So We're a Bad Influence, 1951., 1 item. (Box-folder 8:15)
      In: The New York Times. Review of Bertrand Russell, John Lehman, Sean O'Faolain, J.E.Morpurgo, Martin Cooper, and Perry Miller: The Impact of America on European Culture. Boston, The Beacon Press, 1951.
    - Reviews of The Last Days of Shelley and Byron, edited by J.E.M., 1952-1953., 2 items. (Box-folder 8:16)
      The Folio Society, 1952.
    - Reviews of J.E.M.'s edition of John Keats: A Selection of His Poetry, 1953-1954., 6 items. (Box-folder 8:17)
      Penguin Books, 1953.
    - Reviews of Nye and J.E.M.'s A History of the United States, 1955-1956., 36 items. (Box-folder 8:18)
      Envelope with review clippings, including newspapers from England, France, and Australia.
    - Reviews of Allen Lane: King Penguin, 1979-1981., 4 items. (Box-folder 8:19)
    - Extracts of reviews of Barnes Wallis: A Biography, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 8:20)
    - Review articles on American Excursion, The Autobiography of Leigh Hunt, and Charles Lamb and Elia, n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 8:21)
  Series 15: Writings
- Writings, n.d., 1945-1993. (Box-folder 9-11:30)
    Subseries 15.1: Unpublished manuscripts by J.E.M.
  - Unpublished manuscripts by J.E.M., n.d., [1960?] (Box 9)
    - Red Herrings in the Wood: An Essay on Nonsense Literature, [ca. 1960?]., 1 item. (Box-folder 9:1)
      In his list of publications, J.E.M. notes that a publisher accepted the manuscript, but went bankrupt prior to publication. Includes: title page, contents, and pp. 1-109.
    - Red Herrings, [ca. 1960?]., 1 item. (Box-folder 9:2)
      Pp. 110-207.
    - Red Herrings, [ca. 1960?]., 1 item. (Box-folder 9:3)
      Pp. 208-260.
    - Chapter 5 of Red Herrings, Nonsense and the Americans, [ca. 1960?]., 2 items. (Box-folder 9:4)
      Includes J.E.M.'s notes.
    - Red Herrings in the Wood: An Essay on Nonsense Literature, [ca. 1960?]., 1 item. (Box-folder 9:5)
      Different version.
    - The Moth for the Star, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 9:6)
      pp. 1-100.
    - The Moth for the Star, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 9:7)
      pp. 101-200.
    - The Moth for the Star, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 9:8)
      pp. 201-300.
    - The Moth for the Star, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 9:9)
      pp. 301-400.
    - The Moth for the Star, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 9:10)
      pp. 401-476.
    - For If It Prosper, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 9:11)
      Synopsis.
    - For If It Prosper, n.d., 3 items. (Box-folder 9:12)
      Draft manuscript for historical novel, based on real and fictional characters in eighteenth-century Virginia. Notes and chapters 1 and 2.
    - For If It Prosper, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 9:13)
      Chapter 3.
    - For If It Prosper, n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 9:14)
      Chapter 4.
    - For If It Prosper, n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 9:15)
      Chapter 5 and 6.
    - For If It Prosper, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 9:16)
      Chapter 7.
    - For If It Prosper, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 9:17)
      Chapter 8.
    - For If It Prosper, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 9:18)
      Chapter 9.
    - For If It Prosper, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 9:19)
      Chapter 10.
    - For If It Prosper, n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 9:20)
      Chapters 11 and 12.
    - For If It Prosper, n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 9:21)
      Chapters 13 and 14.
    - For If It Prosper, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 9:22)
      Chapter 15.
    - For If It Prosper, n.d., 3 items. (Box-folder 9:23)
      Brief synopsis, chapter 16 to beginning of final chapter,and final chapter.
    - Untitled, unpublished novel, n.d., 1 item (288 pp.). (Box-folder 9:24-27)
    - Manuscript drafts and fragments, n.d., 5 items. (Box-folder 9:28)
    Subseries 15.2: Radio and television scripts by J.E.M.
  - Radio and television scripts by J.E.M., n.d., 1948-1993. (Box 10)
    - Script to radio broadcast from Phi Beta Kappa Hall in Williamsburg, Virginia, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:1)
      J.E.M. was student director.
    - Poor Major Andre, 30 August 1948., 4 items. (Box-folder 10:2)
      Radio script. Also includes John Andre's The Frantik Lover, a reprint of a poem written by the Major; and a note to J.E.M. from History Today, regarding a manuscript submission.
    - Radio broadcasts about books and the National Book League, c. 195-., 12 items. (Box-folder 10:3)
    - Hollywood: Picture of America?, 7 February 1950., 2 items. (Box-folder 10:4)
      Radio address. Also includes part of an undated essay on Hollywood and Europeans.
    - Travel Talks - Chicago: A City and its Railways, 9 June 1950., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:5)
      BBC Home Service (Schools).
    - Memories of a Westcountry Athlete, 7 July 1950., 2 items. (Box-folder 10:6)
      Includes a note from Secretary to General Programme Assistant at the BBC regarding script revisions, dated 4 July 1950.
    - Geography: North American Tobacco Industry, 6 December 1950., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:7)
      Radio script, BBC Home Service (Schools).
    - Surrender at Yorktown, 3 July 1951., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:8)
      Radio script.
    - Books to Read, 1951., 2 items. (Box-folder 10:9)
      Draft and transcript of the broadcast, written in a review essay-format covering Philip Carman, John Gerard: The Autobiography of an Elizabethan; Jack Simmons, ed.: Journeys in England; Margery Bailey, ed.: Boswell's Column; Hector Bolitho: A Century of British Monarchy; and Hesketh Pearson: Dizzy, (2 drafts, 7 and 9 pp.).
    - Exiled to Virginia, September 1951., 2 items. (Box-folder 10:10)
      Radio script on poet Goronwy Owen, (2 drafts, 3 and 9 pp.).
    - Warm Welcome at Tel Afar, November 1951., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:11)
      Radio script (8 pp.).
    - Travel Talks - Famous Places: The Mississippi, 25 January 1952., 2 items. (Box-folder 10:12)
      Draft and final version (13 pp. each).
    - Report from Britain, 4 April 1952 and 27 May 1952., 2 items. (Box-folder 10:13)
      Radio scripts (4 and 8 pp.).
    - Notes From America, n.d., 1952., 25 items. (Box-folder 10:14)
      Play lists and radio scripts. Includes J.E.M. commentaries. Also includes a booklet of music and lyrics, Kentucky Mountain Ballads Sung By Cousin Emmy (Decca Records, 1948).
    - Radio broadcast on Northampton, Massachusetts, 25 October 1952., items. (Box-folder 10:15)
      Draft essay and notes with a focus on Smith College and the Eisenhower campaign (13 pp.). Also includes a radio script for Transatlantic Mirror - Northampton, Massachusetts and Northampton, England. (Midland Home Service, 10 March 1953). 14 pages. TMS.
    - Trans-Atlantic Mirror: Hereford, Texas and Hereford, England, 27 January 1953., 2 items. (Box-folder 10:16)
      Radio script, Midland Home Service (8 pp). Also includes untitled observations on Hereford, Texas (4 pp.).
    - The American Negro, n.d., 4 items. (Box-folder 10:17)
      3 versions of BBC Home Service (Schools) broadcast. Includes letter from Enid Love, Assistant Head of School Broadcasting, regarding the script and her suggested changes and additions. Final version included.
    - Washington, D.C., 10 March 1953., 2 items. (Box-folder 10:18)
      BBC Home Service (Schools), 2 copies with notes (11 and 14 pp.).
    - Transatlantic Mirror: Hampton, Virginia and Hampton-In-Arden, Warwickshire, 24 March 1953., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:19)
      Midland Home Service (8 pp.).
    - Transatlantic Mirror: Derby, England and Darby, Montana, 7 April 1953., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:20)
    - Travel Talks - The New and the Old in the Americas: Pittsburgh: A Great Industrial City, 28 May 1954., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:21)
      BBC Home Service (Schools) (10 pp.).
    - The House on the Hill, n.d., 5 items. (Box-folder 10:22)
      Drafts of scripts for children's radio program The House on the Hill. Also includes a note from the secretary Peggy Bacon to Miss Anderson, secretary to the Director of the National Book League regarding the scripts, dated 10 August 1955.
    - The House on the Hill, 3 June 1955., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:23)
      Preview article on the children's radio show in Radio Times (p. 21). Entire issue included.
    - The House on the Hill, episode 1: The Norman Keep, 10 June 1955., 1 item (36 pp.). (Box-folder 10:24)
    - The House on the Hill, episode 2: The Lancastrian Castle, 11 June 1955., 1 item (43 pp.). (Box-folder 10:25)
    - The House on the Hill, episode 3: The Tudor House, 24 June 1955., 1 item (40 pp.). (Box-folder 10:26)
    - The House on the Hill, episode 4: The Stuart Shop, 1 July 1955., 1 item (37 pp.). (Box-folder 10:27)
    - The House on the Hill, episode 5: Georgian Residence, 8 July 1955., 1 item (26 pp.). (Box-folder 10:28)
    - The House on the Hill, episode 6: Victorian Villa, 15 July 1955., 1 item (26 pp.). (Box-folder 10:29)
    - Broadcast on Walter de la Mare, 24 April 1956., 2 items (7 and 14 pp.). (Box-folder 10:30)
      2 versions
    - Radio scripts about Joyce Cary, 1956., 3 items. (Box-folder 10:31)
      Includes 3 scripts and interview between J.E.M. and Cary.
    - Untitled radio script for broadcast about J.E.M.'s experience as a bell-hop in an American hotel, 1957., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:32)
    - Radio talk on Lady Chatterley's Lover, 1960., 2 items. (Box-folder 10:33)
      Also a note from the BBC regarding the script.
    - Radio interviews, 1965., 1 item (26 pp., p. 1 is missing). (Box-folder 10:34)
      Includes 4 interviews: 29 November 1965 with J.E.M.; 6 December 1965 with Rosemary Cobham; 11 December 1965 with Walter Allen; 14 December 1965 with John Boynton Priestly.
    - The Americans at Play, 1966., 2 items. (Box-folder 10:35)
      Radio transcript, including a review from The Times.
    - Television script for The Amiable Spy, an account of the life of Major John Andre, 1980., 2 items. (Box-folder 10:36)
    - Extract from The Biography of Barnes Wallis - The Attack of the Dams, 1993., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:37)
      For radio broadcast, includes introduction.
    - Discussion and reading of poetry by J.E.M. and C.N.K.M., n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 10:38)
      2 transcripts, one on war poems and the other on light verse. No indication is made, but C.N.K.M. was probably J.E.M's wife, Catherine.
    - Description of the Reading Room of the British Museum, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:39)
      Transcript.
    - Observations on Woodstock, Illinois relating to election night during Eisenhower-Stevenson presidential race, 195-., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:40)
    - Observations on Lansing, Michigan written during Eisenhower-Stevenson presidential race, 195-., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:41)
    - Observations on New York City during Eisenhower-Stevenson presidential race, 195-., items. (Box-folder 10:42)
    - Other Men's Pleasures, 1948., 5 items. (Box-folder 10:43)
      5 versions of essay on observations of East Lansing, Michigan, written during the Truman presidential campaign.
    - Radio broadcast of observations on Hampton, Virginia, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:44)
    - Radio broadcast of discussion of an evening in Yarmouth, 2 items. (Box-folder 10:45)
      Transcript (16 pp.), includes notes for a travel essay on seaport town of Yarmouth (7 pp.).
    - Essay on the village of Bradwell, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:46)
    - On Understanding Americans, n.d., 1 item (11 pp., p. 1 is missing). (Box-folder 10:47)
    - Transatlantic Mirror: Malvern, Arkansas and Malvern, Worcestershire n.d., 1 item (18 pp., p. 1 is missing). (Box-folder 10:48)
      Transcript, Midland Home Service.
    - Notes on Suggested Midland American Programme, n.d, 1 item. (Box-folder 10:49)
      Proposal for "Transatlantic Mirror" series with potential topics and cities.
    - Correspondence with the British Broadcasting Corporation, various dates., 76 items. (Box-folder 10:50)
      Concerns programming that J.E.M. contributed to or participated in.
    - Correspondence relating to radio and television production and work with the Sexton Agency and Press, 1993-1996., 24 items. (Box-folder 10:51)
      Includes resume of his work in radio and television.
    Subseries 15.3: Poems
  - Poems, n.d., 1945, various dates. (Box-folder 11:1-5)
    - To Our Critics, 5 October 1945., 1 item. (Box-folder 11:1)
      In: Tribune (p. 15), entire issue included.
    - An Aesthetic, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 11:2)
      In: Second Eighteen (pp.31-32).
    - Collection of poems, various dates., 56 items. (Box-folder 11:3)
      Includes handwritten and typed poems. Of particular interest are the poems written during J.E.M.'s service in World War II.
    - Additional poems, n.d., 76 items. (Box-folder 11:4)
      Includes published and unpublished poems.
    - 3 poems, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 11:5)
      Published in Poetry of To-Day: Two Killed in Action, Three Loves, and Blood on Our Tracks (pp. 61-63).
    Subseries 15.4: Unpublished short stories
  - Unpublished short stories, n.d. (Box-folder 11:6-11)
    - Untitles short story, n.d., 2 items (1 notebook and 14 loose sheets; original draft was damaged, photocopy made). (Box-folder 11:6)
      Incomplete draft, includes notes for story.
    - 6 short stories, n.d., 6 items. (Box-folder 11:7)
      Includes: Stare Upon the Ash; Self Inflicted; The Middle East; Substantial Authority; The Brave Man With A Sword - A Short Story By Jonathan More; Advance Party.
    - Warm Welcome in Iraq, n.d., 1 item (14 pp.). (Box-folder 11:8)
    - Detective Story, n.d., 1 item (106 pp.). (Box-folder 11:9)
      Incomplete draft with notes.
    - Preface to an Unwritten School Story, n.d., 1 item (6 pp.). (Box-folder 11:10)
    - Incident in Iran, n.d., 2 items (24 and 27 pp.). (Box-folder 11:11)
      2 different drafts.
    Subseries 15.5: Travel related writings
  - Travel related writings, n.d., 1960, 1985. (Box-folder 11:12-14)
    - Venice, n.d., 3 items. (Box-folder 11:12)
      Introductory essay, including 2 drafts and final published version. No publication listed.
    - Hellenic Cruise Lecture series, 1960., 3 items. (Box-folder 11:13)
    - Florence for Beginners, 1985., 2 items. (Box-folder 11:14)
      For publication in Chicago magazine. Includes letter with editor's suggestions.
    Subseries 15.6: Letters to the Editor and obituaries
  - Letters to the Editor and obituaries, n.d., 1947-1990. (Box-folder 11:18-20)
    - Letters to the editor, 1947., 2 items. (Box-folder 11:18)
      Includes Princeton Men, in: Times Literary Supplement, 8 March 1947; and Letter to the Editor, in: Transatlantic, Summer 1947.
    - Letter to the editor, 1971-1972., 2 items. (Box-folder 11:19)
      Published in: The Times, 19 November 1971; and The Sunday Times, 20 May 1972.
    - Obituaries, 9 items. (Box-folder 11:20)
      Includes are obituaries for the followig individuals: W.H. Portwood, n.d.; C. Worth Howard, 1971; Sam Stewart, 1975; Nansi Pugh, 1970; Douglas Grant, 1969; Professor William Walsh, 1981; Hugh MacLennan, 1990; A.J.M. Smith, 1980; Philip Youngman Carter, n.d.
  Series 16: Genealogical Information
- Genealogical Information, 19--, 2000. (Box-folder 11:15-17)
  - Inventory of Dunmore family papers and related correspondence and clippings, n.d. (Box-folder 11:15)
  - Correspondence and supporting documents concerning J.E.M.'s ancestor, Ezekial Cheever, 19--., 7 items. (Box-folder 11:16)
  - Letter from Michael Seakins to J.E.M., 20 April 2000., 1 item. (Box-folder 11:17)
    Includes genealogical material for family of Robert Thomas Challenor (1775/6-1840). Challenor was a student at Christ's Hospital.
  Series 17: Miscellaneous Non-J.E.M.
- Miscellaneous Non-J.E.M., n.d., 1940-1970. (Box-folder 11:21-30)
  - 18th century folk song, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 11:21)
  - Russel B. Nye: America's First Negro Poet, June 1940., 1 item. (Box-folder 11:22)
    In: Long Island Forum (p. 129).
  - Emile Cammaerts: The Origins of the Belgian Crisis, 1950., 1 item. (Box-folder 11:23)
    Later published in Spectator?
  - 2 articles from The Listener, 5 January 1950., 1 item. (Box-folder 11:24)
    Unknown author: As You Like it?, and What They Are Saying: Broadcast Comments on Far Eastern Events.
  - Sun Life Review, January 1954., 1 item. (Box-folder 11:25)
    Entire issue included.
  - A correspondent: Star-Spangled Literary Spectrum: Enlightening Southern India, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 11:26)
    No publication name visible.
  - Information on Bristol Grammar School, n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 11:27)
    School was attended by Sir Allen Lane. Includes brief article about Lane's role in dedicating a new building and an "Honours List" from 1977-1978.
  - Claire Rayner, Novel Outline, Sisters, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 11:28)